[Waco] Brookview Neighborhood Association records, Inclusive: 1992-2005, undated, Bulk: 1993-1997, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Brookview Neighborhood Association records
Inclusive: 1992-2005, undated, Bulk: 1993-1997, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3700
Brookview Neighborhood Association
6 document boxes
The [Waco] Brookview Neighborhood Association records documents the early stages of development for the community program. Minutes, by-laws, membership rosters, various reports and correspondence are included. A neighborhood housing survey is also available as it was the basis for early projects.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
The Brookview Neighborhood Association was born from the City of Waco Neighborhood Development Program in 1992. The program was created “in an effort to create better communication and relationships between the City and the neighborhoods.” The BNA began planning meetings that year, and in 1993, was issued a Certificate of Incorporation from the State of Texas and received 501(c)(3) non-profit status in 1995.
The BNA began assessing the neighborhood based upon city ordinances and created a Housing Stock and Code Compliance Survey which influenced projects in the beginning of the organization. The association holds clean up events, usually in conjunction with the Baylor University Steppin’ Out program, garage sales, and other activities throughout the year. As of 2021, the association is still in operation.
Scope and Content
The [Waco] Brookview Neighborhood Association records are a limited look at the early workings of the organization from incorporation through the first decade of existence.
The Administrative series includes minutes, financial and budgeting reports, by-laws, neighborhood maps, and introduces the relationship between the association and the City of Waco.
The Correspondence series serves as a field for general relations between the BNA and the City of Waco as well as between the organization and the community. Interestingly, some correspondence mentions the use of private, non-profit 501(c)(3) materials being used in conjunction with The Waco Citizen, a for profit newspaper.
The Projects and Outreach series covers the actions taken to enhance the community. Information on applications for the Community Development Block Grants and a Housing Stock and Code Compliance Survey are included. The survey was conducted as a starting point to improve upon City of Waco code violations being committed throughout the neighborhood. Participation in the Baylor University Steppin’ Out program as well as yard of the month activities are documented.
Arrangement
The collection had no prior arrangement. Previous staff identified and labeled folder contents. Folder titles remained but were updated and clarified as necessary. The collection is now in three series, Series I: Administrative, Series II: Correspondence, and Series III: Projects and Outreach.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3700. Acquired 2007-09-14
Related Resources
Related references
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Brookview Neighborhood Association (Waco, Tex.)
Subjects
Citizens' associations -- Texas -- Waco.; Community development -- Texas -- Waco.; Real property surveys -- Texas -- Waco.
Genres
By-laws.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Membership lists.; Minutes (Records); Photographs.
- Administrative, 1992-2005; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  The Administrative Series, dated 1992-2005, includes minutes, by-laws, membership rosters, committee reports, neighborhood maps, and city budget information. The series is arranged in chronological order and is in good condition.
  - Action Committee, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Proposed Description for City of Waco Neighborhood Development Program, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Proposal for Neighborhood Development Program & By-Laws, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Steering Committee, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Business Committee, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 501 (C)(3) Application, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Articles of Incorporation, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer’s Reports, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Waco Neighborhood Association Forum, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - By-Laws, 1993, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Empowerment Zone/Enterprise Community Planning, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1994 -1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Recycling Advisory Committee Proposal, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Membership List, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City of Waco Recycling Advisory Committee (1 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - City of Waco Recycling Advisory Committee (2 of 2), 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1995—2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Public Relations Committee, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Goals, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Budgetary Process, Waco Neighborhood Association (1 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Budgetary Process, Waco Neighborhood Association (2 of 2), 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Membership Rosters, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Budgetary Process, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - By-Laws Revisions, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - By-Laws Revisions, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Membership Lists, 1999-2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - City of Waco Comprehensive Plan & Zoning Ordinance, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1994-2001; 2
  The Correspondence series, dated 1994-2001, includes thank you notes, press releases, correspondence from the mayor and city, Brookview Neighborhood Association goals, and flyers promoting community events. The series is arranged chronologically and in good condition.
  - General, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Projects and Outreach, 1993-2004, undated; 3
  The Projects and Outreach series, dated 1993-2004, documents the early involvement of the organization in the Brookview Neighborhood. Photographs, newsletters, volunteer information, clippings, and other pamphlets are included along with a housing survey of the neighborhood. The series is arranged chronologically and in good condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Floppy disk; Photographic print
  - Photographs, Christmas Lights, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, Clean Up Your Act, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Housing, Pamphlets, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Membership Forms, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Code Enforcement Pamphlet, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Membership Pamphlets & Newsletters (Floppy Disks), undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Steppin’ Out, Fall, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Steppin’ Out, Spring, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Community Development Block Grant Proposal, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Guthrie Park & Greenbelt Planning, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - City of Waco Budgetary Process, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newsletters, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newsletters, 1993-2004 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Community Development Block Grant Proposal, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Steppin’ Out, Spring, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1994-2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Waco Vision 2020 (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Waco Vision 2020 (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Housing Survey (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Housing Survey (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Recycling, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (1 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (2 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (3 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (4 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (5 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (6 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (7 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (8 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (9 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (10 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (11 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (12 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (13 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (14 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (15 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (16 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (17 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (18 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (19 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Housing Stock & Code Compliance Survey (20 of 20), 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - General, 1995-2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Crime Prevention & Neighborhood Watch, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Photographs, Lighted Night Out, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Recycling, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Steppin’ Out, Spring, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Resident’s Survey, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Newsletters & Publicity, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 20)